Austin Croucher

WEB DEVELOPER

austin.croucher@gmail.com 647-968-7298

linkedin.com/in/austincroucher https://austincroucher.netlify.app/ https://github.com/AustinCroucher247

PROFILE

As a software engineer with over 15 years of restaurant industry background, including 10 as manager, I bring a unique blend of skills to the table. Through training numerous employees with diverse educational, cultural and language backgrounds, I have honed my team-building abilities to a high level. My philosophy degree has also equipped me with strong logical problem-solving skills, and critical thinking skills, which I have applied to my work in software engineering.

My interpersonal skills, developed through years of managing a restaurant team, will enable me to collaborate seamlessly with colleagues, while my logical and analytical thought processes will translate perfectly into programming, given the inherent local nature of coding.

SKILLS

HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Node, React, Express, MySQL, Agile Development, Document Object Model (DOM) API's, Web API's, User Authentication, OAuth, Heroku, Github, Jest

EXPERIENCE

General Manager | Cafe Landwer

JAN 2019 - FEB 2022, North York, ON

- Functioned proficiently in a high intensity environment.
- Coordinated the logistics for both the front and back of house (85+ people) leading to a successful \$3,000,000/yr revenue restaurant
- Delegated tasks to the team in order to create an organized umbrella of authority

Bar Manager | Milestones

JAN 2015 - JAN 2019, Richmond Hill, ON

- Built a new system of organization of inventory for accurate counts, limiting loss and eliminating inefficiencies
- Achieved highest alcohol sales and lowest cost of any Milestones in Ontario by margin of 10% due to the system I created

Guest Experience Manager | Lonestar Texas Grill

JAN 2012 - JAN 2015, Richmond Hill, ON

 Oversaw the general guest experience for the restaurant and created a standard and then delegated instructions on how to adhere to said standard

EDUCATION

BrainStation | Diploma, Software Engineering

JAN 2023 - APR 2023, Toronto, ON

York University | Certificate in Conflict Resolution

JAN 2014 - 2015, Vaughan, ON

York University | Bachelors of Arts in Philosophy

JAN 2010 - 2014, Vaughan, ON

• Graduated with Honors

PROJECTS

Retro Rumble - Retro Arcade Game Website (Lead coder)

JAN 2023, BrainStation

- Using React to build out the front end,node/express for the backend and integrated websockets, developed a fully functional gaming website where people can watch people play games live
- Added a login page which allows the user to check their scores on a global leaderboard across all games.
- Built an entire database structure using mySQL to hold leaderboard and user data